Dreams and nightmares are bound together,
that which you imagine…
imagines you.
THE PRINCE
Mommy… I'd like to visit their world!
You're already there.
Whenever you write,
or when you draw,
your soul… is ink.
That's how they exist.
They all become as real…
as you.
Do you think they can see me?
Mommy!
Help us!
What is it, mommy!
Help us! Help us, Grandma, help me!
Mom?
Please! Help us!
-Oh, no…
-Oh…
Francisca! Leave that thing!
Come help me!
Ah…
MARÍA CONCHITA PAREDES DIOSDADO
BELOVED MOTHER AND WIFE
Mm. I'm so sorry, Francisca.
Huh?
Hm… Mh-hm.
Francisca!
-Oh, no!
-Come back here!
Francisca, where are you?
Mh.
-Please help me find my granddaughter,
-Francisca!
Right now!
Francisca!
You little brat! Where are you hiding?
Francisca, where are you?
The…
sweet young…
prince…
would do anything necessary to save his
parents…
And everyone he loved.
Mhh…
Ah! I found the girl, ma'am.
Oh, Francisca!
How dare you do this to us today?
Oh!
Oh.
Hm…
-Francisca? The sun's about to come up.
-Mhh…
Mh. Ah.
Understood.
All clear in the east wing.
Oh, Fabulist, you scared me!
Here, come with me.
All good, sir.
Hm…
Mh.
An inexplicable desire to understand
-more stirred within the prince.
-What?
-He decided to listen to his instinct.
-Huh?
Following his intuition…
and a mysterious voice calling him.
He felt uneasy,
-but he wasn't afraid. An odd emotion
-Ow!
Came over him, as he sensed he
was meeting his destiny.
He climbed and climbed… searching
for a way out of his monstrous world,
-as the voice calling for him
-Oh!
Grew more real with each passing moment.
He was astonished to discover he
had reached the most peculiar place.
One he had never been to before.
Oh, ugh…
Confusion overwhelmed him, his tummy
was hurting.
Ah…
-Huh?
-He found himself in this new place full
-of strangers.
-Hm?
An unseen dream land…
A- fantastic place!
She's a little crazy, don't you think,
-buddy?
-Mh-hm
-Just "a little", really?
-She's terrifying, buddy.
Oh…
She's only seeking attention.
I'll be the first to get to
the classroom.
-I know, right? Poor thing.
-No, you can't beat me!
-I've always thought her stories were
-Do you want to come over to my
-strange,
-house after Sunday school?
If he keeps running like that, he's gonna
fall.
I know, buddy, he's very clumsy, and he
always ends up covered in bruises
I bet the priest hasn't noticed I hid his
chalk.
Sure, when my dad comes pick me
up, we'll ask him if I can go.
And scrapes.
Oh!
Huh?
Eh…
Eh?
Ah! Ahh!
Eh… No! Ah…
Ehm…
Ah…
Ehm… Oh…
Mhh, I liked it very much.
And my father is in the publishing
business.
I think he might like your stories
someday,
-I'm Uhgu-
-Yeah, right, you're so funny. Why are
you all so mean to me?
Ahhh!
Huh?
Ah…
Ow…
Huh?
Mh…
Ah! Ah…
-Huh?
-Ahh!
Francisca!
You little menace!
-Grandma, there's a monster!
-Oh, my goodness!
Why are you here?
Father Cosme already told me
that after recess you didn't come
back to the classroom,
and that you've been scaring the
rest of the children.
Grandma!
There's a creature in those plants.
Hm.
Ah…
Ugh! I saw nothing.
Why are you like this? Wouldn't you
-like to be like your peers? Maybe then
-Ah!
You'd finally have a friend.
Ahh!
You're nothing but a witch!
Huh?
What did you call me?
-Ah…
-You little brat.
-Ow!
-Ah!
Oh!
Ah!
Ow! Ow!
Oh-oh.
I'm sorry, but guess what happened today.
I was fast asleep and, uhm…
Mh… Oh, are you all right, sweetheart?
Yes, Mom… I'm fine.
-Veritena.
-Woah!
-My love.
-Stop it, Mom!
If you hug him like that,
he'll think that what he did was right.
I'm hugging my son… before I ground him
for the rest of his life.
What?
-Ficturo!
-Dad!
Are you alright?
Huh?
Oh…
Oh, that king and his useless royal
family will bring about our downfall.
Uhm… Eh…
You have to consider the consequences
of your actions,
we won't always be here to protect you.
But I wasn't hurt at all!
I actually discovered something amazing!
I found out we can use the Harpspider
to go somewhere else,
I have to tell you what I just-
No, Herneval! No!
You need to understand
that what you just did was outrageously
dangerous, son.
My love, you must be more cautious.
There's a balance between the two realms
and it's our duty to protect it.
No one has been able to cross in a
very long time, son,
and it's better that way.
Promise me no one will know what
you discovered.
Yes, I'm sorry.
Besides…
you damaged our species' most important
instrument…
the Harpspider.
-Woah!
-You must protect it, for one day you
will play it
and by doing so you will shape the human
subconscious.
That is our gift…
-solely reserved for the members of the
-Mh…
royal family.
Ficturo,
the time has come for him to know.
-Huh?
-What? Have you lost your mind, Veritena?
Eh…
-He's still way too young to understand.
-What?
I'm not "too young"!
I want to know what's on the other side.
There was a girl
surrounded by light.
I don't get it!
A voice was talking to me, or was it
-talking about me?
-Aw.
-How does she know me?
-Ah!
-Hm.
-She even mentioned I was the prince,
how could she know? Ah! How?
How can she know me so well?
Hm.
-Her voice sounds familiar, but I don't
-Huh?
Know who she is.
Do you know what that means?
Ah…
Calm down, we share history with
the humankind.
They tell stories and then they are…
Fiction. That becomes reality.
Humans are afraid to dream.
-Fiction and truth.
-Two sides of view.
-Constellation in full, you're a
-paradox deep with hymn.
The fiction becomes now woven from
threads of ferocity.
Fiction and dreams of yesteryear
reveal the truth and stay untouched by
the lies.
-Fiction and truth.
-Two sides of view.
-Constellation in full, you're a
-paradox deep with hymn.
This realm is the home to the fears
of humankind,
-we are the ideas that frighten them.
-Huh?
So we're just ideas?
Does that mean… we don't exist?
Oh
Do you really feel like you don't exist?
-Mhh… Mh…
-Oh!
Ehm… Eh…
-You are a sweet dream.
-You are the truth.
-And fiction too.
-You are word.
-You are a sweet dream.
-You are the truth.
-And fiction too.
-You are word.
-Truth is not a solute. There is no such
Ah.
-Thing, therefore
-Thing, therefore You're real.
You're real.
Ahh!
-Ahh!
-Ah, Ficturo!
-Oh… It's alright.
-Ah!
-What was that?
-Relax.
-I don't know!
-To the throne chamber!
Your Majesties,
do you need help?
Thank you, Captain Mythelitas.
I'm afraid there's nothing more we can do
for the King.
Eh… Uh…
Forgive me for troubling you, but the…
-Excuse me, I-
-Royal Nightmare Maker…
demands to have a hearing with Your
Majesties…
immediately.
Dad!
Shall I let him in?
There's no time for these… formalities!
They're… Uh… uh…
They're outrageous!
-That's enough!
-Huh?
Hold it.
Your Majesty!
There has been a terrible,
ruinous and very scandalous fluctuation
between the realms!
Captain!
Holy shadows, Your Majesty!
-You look absolutely awful.
-Eh.
Oh…
Uh… I wonder if it's time to review the
proposal that I…
Procustes…
this is hardly the right moment.
Huh?
-Have the prince taken to his chambers,
-What?
If you would.
My young master,
Eh… would you come with me?
Mh. Mh… Oh…
Here, dad.
Mhh… Oh…
-Hey…
-Do as I say, son.
Uh… Hm.
Huh?
Uh…
Uh… Uh… no, wait! Procustes…
Yes… Your Highness?
What's wrong with my parents?
Well, uhm…
you see…
a heavy burden rests upon the
shoulders of the King and Queen, my Lord.
Our kind grows weaker.
Its strength, its vigor, its presence,
all slipping away,
because of the human scum.
-Your parents are the first ones to
-Ow…
feel it, and the kingdom follows.
No, I won't allow it!
I'm going to help them
Oh, I really wish you could, but…
Huh?
I'm afraid it's out of your hands, my
Lord.
-But once they're gone,
-Uhm…
-Eh, eh…
-you and I shall work together as one.
I will share my masterpieces so that
you may send them to humankind
in the form of horrific nightmares.
Hm… Ow…
Unfortunately we live at the mercy
of those simple and
brutish
-creatures.
-Hm.
No! I don't want to depend on humans!
Ay…
if only we were able to cross over to the
Realm of Existence…
this would be a different story.
And… is there…
anyone who can cross over?
In an age long forgotten,
a very long time ago,
Fear of fear itself found its form.
And a colossal feathered spider was born:
The magnificent Enkara.
Enkara realized her life was tethered to
the fear she awakened in the hearts of
humans.
She used the Harpspider to cross and
thus subjugate the humans.
Then the impertinent Ceimut
defended humankind
and challenged Enkara
to a mighty battle.
But Enkara captured Ceimut
and devoured him.
Using his fangs and his spines,
-Ceimut tore Enkara's throat open
-Ahh!
And escaped.
Enkara was no more
and from her remains
two new species came into being:
From her feathers…
Tecothians, just like me!
Yes, that's right!
And from Enkara's silken webs,
the Aradithians, like me, were born.
Yet in these days we don't have enough
power to materialize in the Realm of
Existence.
Ah, but I just…
Mh,
-You have just what, my Lord?
-uh…
Uhm… I have just… remembered… that I'm
a little tired.
Hm.
Of course, of course, Your Highness!
How foolish of me to trouble you
with such grown-up matters.
Uh… I extend to you a cordial,
genuine, and most deeply sincere apology.
May you have the sweetest of nightmares.
Thank you.
Mh…
Eww!
Old socks are the worst in the entire
world!
Just gross!
Stop whining, Francisca Imelda,
-Hm…
-as women,
this has to be our duty.
What I really want is to be a writer!
I'll write about the being I saw
last night!
Those terror stories of yours.
That's it! A terror is what I saw!
Stop with this nonsense!
You have a wild imagination,
but you'll grow out of it.
-Ah…
-They have even…
spoken of…
-crossing over to the Realm of Existence.
-Huh?
The two realms must always remain
separate,
How? Mh.
Why can't they understand that
without that balance,
we simply would not exist?
I understand,
but they have been giving too much heed
to
Procustes.
I know he's been by your side for an
entire era, but…
have you considered…
getting rid of him?
-Huh?
-No, no, no, no, no.
Declaring war would only make
the situation worse.
His ability as a Nightmare Maker
to travel with his consciousness
has become too dangerous.
-I'd rather keep him under close watch.
-Oh…
Oh… my dear Saymut,
I know you risk a great deal in bringing
me this message.
You have proven yourself a true friend.
I'll think on what to do.
Don't take too long Ficturo, the Chiefs
are growing impatient,
they won't stand idly by
as all their clans fade away.
I truly appreciate your advice, my old
friend.
The Topus Terrentus…
is in grave danger.
10 YEARS LATER
Thank you for joining me, Mythelitas.
I needed to clear my head.
I'm… at your service.
I'm concerned about our realm, there's…
nothing I can do.
It's none of my business, Your Highness,
but…
have you taken a look at the Royal
Nightmare Maker's latest stories?
Ah! Prince Herneval!
No.
Tell me why has the royal family
abandoned us?
Why won't you act to prevent our demise?
Long live Procuestes!
The only noble terror who truly
cares about us!
Ah! Agh!
No! No! Please don't!
We will all slowly fade away.
Uh… uh… What do I do?
Ah-
No…
No!
We need to make a change.
My stories!
I thought I told you that little girls
cannot be writers.
Today is the day, my dear terrors,
the world is finally going to meet you.
Ah…
I implore you, Your Majesty…
uh… I must insist one more time.
Ficturo… don't!
Ah…
If you would only allow me,
I would do my very best
to assemble the wisest terrors and
find a way to cross over.
Uh… it's your responsibility as the royal
family to save us from the-
That's enough, Procustes.
-Oh!
-Now leave us.
Guards, show Procustes the way out.
Yes, sir.
He's gone, Dad.
Mh…
Thank you, son.
Mom?
Oh, hi, my beautiful son.
Herneval,
I think you're losing weight, son.
Have you been eating correctly?
Mom… I'm alright,
what about you?
Are you unwell?
No.
Bring them.
I just need some nightmares,
it's nothing.
CLASSIC NIGHTMARES VOLUME XIII
BY PROCUSTES
Let's see…
For years, Procustes has failed in his
promise of a masterpiece.
Ah.
What do we have here…?
Ow!
Oh… the nightmares of today are not
what they once were.
-Ow…
-Mom!
Uh, no, please don't worry, honey.
What matters above all is that you are
safe and well.
No, but- how can you tell me not to
worry?
Your mother and I have done everything we
could,
-if only we had more time and strength…
-Mh.
The time has come for you to make the
decisions for the Topus Terrentus.
This is garbage!
Don't underestimate Procustes.
Each and every decision you make
will have infinite consequences.
-Procustes!
-Ahh!
Your Highness!
Uh…
I was right in the middle of my-
uh… he he he…
daily writing session.
Doesn't look like it.
Uh- uh…
well, you wouldn't understand this,
but uh-
it is vital that a writer have time
to himself,
time for leisure and…
and to do other…
things.
That's what concerns me.
My parents are very sick.
Of course, that is due to the fact that
nowadays it's difficult to remain
healthy so…
I think it's due to your stories.
Uh, ahm.
The nightmares you write no longer
frighten the humans.
Ah. Because humans are all wrong!
The people must always bear the blame!
I want to bring in another writer,
a human.
That's blasphemy! That's nonsense!
There can't be two Royal Nightmare
Makers!
How could a human even hope to cross?
I believe I've already figured it out.
The time to change has come.
As it happens, I am finishing my latest
masterpiece.
Just be patient my young master.
You'll witness the quality of my
nightmares.
I've had enough patience and you know it.
Ahh!
He's a very holy man.
And… he's been preaching for a long time.
Francisca!
-Hi there.
-Oh!
Uh… Augusto!
I'm on my way to see your father at his
editorial office.
Yes, I know.
I just wanted to wish you luck. Uh-
n- not that you need it, of course,
the thing is- that my father can be an
expert in discouraging sometimes but-
you'll do just fine.
Alright, then… I'll go find out?
Right, right.
Sure.
Mh… hm…
Ehm… Alright…
-good to see you.
-Of course.
Oh!
And uhm… uh- wha- wha- whatever happens,
your stories have been…
fascinating,
since we were young.
Ugh!
My dear Miss Francisca Imelda,
such a fine lady like you shouldn't be
writing
these uh…
horrible… stories.
-Don't drag your good name in the mud.
-Uh…
But did you at least read one?
I would never waste my precious
time reading this…
piece of trash!
Art, literature,
should emulate reality,
not create
a new one.
-Wait! Oh…
-Uh…
You were right all along, Grandma.
And now I quit!
Mh.
BY FRANCISCA IMELDA
BY FRANKELDA
If Francisca Imelda couldn't do it,
Frankelda will certainly succeed!
I will become the best writer I can be
in fantasy and horror.
Forgive me, Francisca. Did I scare you?
We've… met before.
Sure we have, when we were kids.
It is you!
And I have read all the stories you've
written.
Oof! All real masterpieces.
I'm Herneval, Prince of Terrors,
just the way you named our species.
-Even though we live in hiding, you
-But don't you…
have managed to capture our very
essence in a…
sublime way.
That's why I'm here,
because I require your help.
My help?
But you don't exist!
I don't exist?
What's real and what's not?
We live in a different dimension that you
peek into when you write.
Oh!
-Uh…
-Mh…
Nowadays you all have a logical
explanation for every single nightmare
that we send you.
Are you the creators of our nightmares?
Yes,
the Royal Nightmare Maker creates them,
we all depend on his… "talent",
but he's too outdated now.
Ah…
He writes one cliché after another.
But maybe if we had better stories…
What are you saying?
Don't be afraid,
I'm your biggest fan,
I would never hurt you,
we just need to understand humans a
little bit better.
What are humans afraid of now?
Mhh…
Our inner selves.
Mhh!
Very interesting.
Please, you have to help us.
Mh. No…
I will go! How do we get there?
Only your consciousness is allowed
to come.
What? But how am I…?
I will help you with that.
Mhh… No, hold on.
You have to relax a little.
Why don't you try reading me the last
poem you wrote?
You think we're alone here, that the
night is ours but there are some secrets
in our deepest nightmares.
It's my ink that stares at us, and my
eyes are scrambling. Dwelling in the
shadows, in the pages they're hiding.
And it's not so dreadful, you can
see the unknown when you read through.
This invisible ink that now lives
without a breath, an author who's…
And it's not so dreadful, you can see the
unknown when you read through. This
invisible ink that now lives without a
breath, an author who's…
A Terror!
Come with me, Francisca.
Not Francisca.
I am Frankelda!
A human writer?
Never have I been so grievously afronted.
Neither I nor any of the Seven Clans.
Hmm…
Perhaps your idea isn't that bad after
all, my dearest little Prince.
Oh!
Mh.
Hm? It won't be long now, my Goddess,
the Seven Clans have begun to assemble.
Clan of the Magic… is present.
Aluxastli!
Here come Dubium and Timet from
the Clan of the Psyche.
Ugh…
-Ceimut from the Clan of the Primal.
-Ahh!
Milady Siren from the Clan of the Depths,
thank you for coming.
Bloodsucker from the Clan of the
-Darkness,
-Ahh!
And her… goat.
Oh!
Lady Coyote from the Clan of the
Death graces us with her presence,
how wonderful-
I have been summoned to a most pressing
meeting to
protect the Realm of Terrors from its
ruin!
According to a…
message of utmost… importance.
Don Coco's here.
-I can't imagine what could be so vital
-Uh… Ow!
As to compel me to cancel
all of my plans today.
Explain yourself at once,
-Royal Nightmare Maker!
-Yes, of course
Don Coco from the Clan of the Robbery.
It is a prodigious honor
for yours truly to stand before such
illustrious and baleful
Chiefs of the Seven Clans.
We must pledge ourselves to determine the
fate of our beloved Topus Terrentus.
-That's insane!
-Huh?
-First the royal couple.
-Oh, no!
But then we will inevitably follow!
Bit by bit we will all
meet our end!
What we need is to trust Our Majesties,
this realm…
wouldn't even exist without them,
show some honor…
-and speak to them
-Bah…
face-to-face.
I think I may have a solution.
I have summoned you,
my brutal colleagues,
because I recently made an unprecedented
discovery.
I witnessed something extraordinary.
With all these eyes of mine,
I looked on as young Prince Herneval
crossed through the portal
-to the Realm of Existence.
-Oh, no! How?
-That's impossible!
-No way?
-Say what?
-Seriously?
Someone would have to think about him
all the time.
And that!
Confirms my hypothesis,
which the King and Queen have dismissed
in outrage
and even mockery
countless times.
But I won't be silent anymore!
Not while I can still save you,
and your clans
by trying to find a way to invade
-the Realm of Existence.
-Huh?
There is no other way!
And that's why…
I dare today
to ask for your support
to claim control of this realm.
So that we may finally…
-behold a new era.
-Oh!
Well…
-Do you think it could work? If only
-I'm sorry I don't think so.
That's a terrible plan.
-Maybe we could try.
-We could…
-{Enkarik]
-Ah!
She's right!
What if the problem with this realm
is the Royal Nightmare Maker's stories?
How can we even consider crossing over
if we are less and less relevant to
the humans?
Someone had to say it.
-Well yes? That could be true?
-She's right.
What have you been
working on lately, Procustes?
Show us your nightmares at once!
That is a good idea, right?
How dare you question my artistry?
No one could ever write the way I do!
My… dramatic talent is exceptional!
My prose truly glows,
and my rhyme is simply sublime!
My stories are…
Clichés!
Well why don't you prove your worth?
Show us your most recent writings.
I will do so!
I will show you my latest masterpiece,
and you'll see that I am not to blame for
this most-
mh-
embarrassing situation.
-Let us hope your promises materialize
-Is he really going to do that?
I doubt he has even a single word
written.
This time.
Let's go home, Macaria.
-We'll see about that.
-I don't believe him.
Come on, hurry, sweetie.
Wow!
Woah!
Mh.
I think you two will like each other.
Come!
What is this place?
-This is my home.
-But uh… is this real or imaginary?
How many types of terrors are there?
-Mh…
-Is a monster the same as a terror?
How long does an average terror live?
How long have we been here?
Well, you'll see, time passes a little
differently here.
Ah! Tell me exactly how?
How long is an hour here versus
an hour in-?
You can't really understand the Realm
of Terrors using the reasoning of the
Realm of Existence.
This whole place…
what lies within?
Drama, horror, and mystery too
It's the work of an author who
has refined and shaped her mind.
Welcome to your inner world!
I've been in this place before.
Intuition, wit, and craft
in the service of our art,
can reveal this hidden truth.
This place is made out of you.
I've been in this place before. A dream
written into existing. I've been in this
place before. A memory bottled burried.
This is my dream world thoughts
and words are brought to life.
This is my dream world thoughts and words
are brought to life.
I have crossed beyond the veil.
A strange and other worldly realm.
It is more real than reality.
I've been in this place before.
You envision and you see or perhaps
the reverse may be. Writing what you
behold, you return to us again.
-Welcome to my kingdom, a place you can
-I've been in this place before a dream
-call home Welcome to my kingdom,
-written into existing. I've been in this
-where you can dream and wander. This is
-place before A memory far and burried.
-My dream world Thoughts and words
-This is my dream world Thoughts
-are brought to life.
-and words are brought to life.
-I have crossed the other veil, a strange
-Welcome to your inner world, It's a
-and other worldly realm. It is more real
-place made out of you.
-Than reality, I've been in this
-You return to us again, a place you can
-place before.
-call home.
-Uh, uh…
-Mh…
Welcome to the Topus Terrentus,
the Realm of Terrors.
Thank you!
Ah…
Wow!
Wow…
Frankelda,
meet my parents.
It's… an honor to meet you.
-Welcome, my dear child.
-Ah…
well, thank you.
-Mh.
-Bravo!
The exceedingly gifted human writer has
finally arrived!
Uh… "Exceedingly gifted"?
Yes! The Prince has been talking
about you non-stop.
Ah! Eh…
Frankelda,
please meet Procustes.
The one and only Royal Nightmare Maker,
at your service.
Mh…
Pleased to meet you.
I'm profoundly eager to read your
wonderful stories.
Oh, of course! Here they are, hope you
-find them to your liking.
-Uh…
-Yes! Perhaps I could take them to…
-Procustes!
Read them here instead,
that way Frankelda can…
see how you react.
-Right?
-As you wish, your Highness…
Mh…
Oi…
Mh, ah.
… Absolute certainty.
-The ghosts went about with their arms
-Huh?
Outstretched, acting foolishly.
-She shut her eyes, swallowed, and went on
-Ah…
playing.
-Consumed by tears born of her
-Huh…
own passion.
Her eyes widened in surprise, but her
-expression did not change.
-Ow…
El Coco removed his hat, from which the
passions of other children emerge as
ghosts.
Baton in hand, El Coco began a painful
concert for his slaves, who broke into
near-silent sobbing.
-Tell me.
-Uh… Yes?
What motivates you to write?
Well…
to get away…
from my reality.
My writing flows when I unburden my
thoughts.
-I see now…
-Uh, uh… but…
what do you…
mh, think of them?
They're- not that bad,
they're fine overall,
they're not much to speak of
honestly but,
I mean, some of the stories are…
bland, flat…
boring… ordinary.
-Oh…
-Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
Don't take it like that.
It's not such bad work, for something
written by a…
an… amateur.
But, well it's important, as you're just
starting, that you don't let delusions
of grandeur get the better of you.
If you'll allow me, I would be
truly pleased to share the professional
wisdom I have amassed throughout my most
prolific
writing career.
Ah… uh, uh,
uh, yes, yes, you're very kind to me.
I believe you lack structure.
Uh…
The characters' motivations are unclear,
tell you what,
I'm going to give you a
copy of my Sinister Writing Handbook,
a book I wrote myself,
where you can find a step-by-step
guide to writing…
-properly.
-Thank you.
-You're so kind.
-Alright…
let's just call it a day.
We'll talk later, Procustes.
Certainly, Your Highness,
I simply can't wait.
No, wait!
Oh… uh… uh…
My book,
if you will.
Come in.
Ah…
I spent hours in this room when I was
a kid.
These books contain the literature and
history of the Terrors.
Fascinating!
I love it!
You can stay here if you want.
Uh… uh…
I have to go back soon.
I appreciate it.
Procustes is…
a jealous terror.
How can I be certain you're telling the
truth?
When I read your stories I'm
not Herneval,
I'm one of your hundreds of characters.
And when I'm not reading them…
the only thing I can think about is uh…
is uh…
It's your stories.
-Mh.
-I really want to trust in you…
but…
-can I?
-Yes.
And I beg you- never to doubt your talent.
Ah… mh… ah…
Ah!
Uh…
Hm…
uhm…
ONCE UPON...
“Well, no way, sir.
I won't let you leave here.
Ever again".
-Amazing.
-You think so?
Ha! Uh, listen,
there's something I need to tell you.
This realm is…
so captivating!
Oh…
-Uh, uh… Frankelda, hear me out.
-This gives me so many ideas.
-I need you to help me.
-I…
don't know if I can be of any help.
Heh-heh…
You can do more than you can imagine.
Uh…
I don't even know how to say this.
And maybe it's a bit rushed, I know, but
uh-
Uh… time's running out.
If we don't do something, we'll all be
gone soon.
Uh… what I really mean, uhm-
well, I'm just… uh, uhm…
uh, uh…
I wanted to ask if you'd like to be
uh the Royal Nightmare Maker?
-You mean stay here?
-Mh…
I know it's too much, but…
I think it might be good for…
obviously for all of us, but also…
it'd be good for… for you.
I don't think I'm up to par.
I know you are. I'll prove it to you.
Let me borrow your book, so my parents
can craft new nightmares.
Uh…
I'm sure your stories will revitalize
the Topus Terrentus.
Uh… Uh, uh…
So your parents are going to read my
stories?
Please! We need them!
Trust in me.
I trust in you.
What a splendid day to change the course
of history!
Oh…
Today will be remembered as the day
when writers cast aside their egos
to preserve the
Topus Terrentus.
What is going on?
What? Ha!
Hasn't His Highness told you what he
promised to do?
No…
We… agreed he would ask you for your book
giving me the opportunity to improve
-your stories.
-Uh…
-That's not what…
-What a plan! He's a genius strategist
Uh, Franke…
Now your kind will know our
great stories.
You'll be the assistant to the greatest
-author who ever lived!
-What are you…
Yours truly!
How could you do this?
Frankelda, that's not what…
But Your Highness, we discussed this
yesterday.
I will deal with you later!
This is a terrible misunderstanding,
-my Lord! Ow…
-Get off me!
Frankelda! It's not what you think!
Procustes is…
Procustes is the only one who's been
honest here!
He's always made it clear how mediocre
I am!
Leave me alone! Leave me at once!
Uh, uh… we'll talk tomorrow.
No! No!
Tomorrow I leave this place for good.
I don't want to hear about the terrors
or you.
Ah…
Your Highness.
How did you know I was here?
Just leave!
With everyone's cooperation,
I'm confident that, together, we can
find a way through this predicament,
my Lord. Ah…
if only she could stay one more day
in this realm.
It's too late for that.
No, it's not.
If we send your friend a petty, trivial,
insignificant nightmare tonight
-maybe she'll remember how awful her
-What?
Life is in the Realm of Existence,
and she might even consider staying a
-bit longer.
-Uh…
that would be painful for her.
No, no!
No! No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Heh… well, not too much,
just… enough to… convince her to stay,
and prevent your parents and the
kingdom from dying.
Alright…
but I'll be the one to supervise
the nightmare.
Oh, of course, my Lord!
I just have to write about something very
specific in her life.
Oh… Uh.
-Do you have any suggestions?
-Oh…
Write about her grandmother.
Ha!
Hmm…
Forgive me, Frankelda.
Mh. Mh.
Mh.
Now listen up, child!
You are not leaving this house
until you finish mending
each and every sock in that pile!
Not one book!
Maybe then you'll stop going around
calling me "witch."
Let's find out how the writer
unburdens her thoughts.
Agh!
Francisca always woke up right before the
sunrise
so she could make breakfast for her ten
older siblings,
all of them men,
they used to work in the silver mines
along with their father
who was the owner.
As nighttime was not enough,
she used any opportunity she had to…
Hmm…
What? A hen-witch?
Called Totolina? Well, it's… uh…
Oh…
Oh!
It's good! Uh…
It's… magnificent!
Oh! Uh… this story could be a milestone
in the history of Topus Terrentus!
Oh! And it's mine!
-Hello, my dear!
-Oh!
Frankelda, please join us!
Good morning, Your Majesties.
Do you know how I can go back to
my realm?
You can't leave without first reading
Procustes's new stories.
Characters with desires,
fears and insecurities.
Irony… suffering…
learning and personal growth.
So good
that I find it hard to believe that
they are Procustes'.
Uh…
No. Ah…
What?
These are the dreams I had last night.
I was going to write them down today,
you sent me those nightmares about…
No, Frankelda,
we don't know what you're talking about.
You!
You. You!
You traitor!
You were right, son, all we ever needed
were new stories.
But I suspect…
they weren't written by he who claims to
have done so.
Am I right?
I don't get it.
Wait… what? No, no! No, no, no!
He stole them while Frankelda was
dreaming!
-Go to her.
-We have to fix this right now!
Frankelda!
I underestimated Procustes.
Forgive me, I'll fix it.
I'm such a fool.
This… is where we give up, isn't it?
No!
You stole it all!
You even stole- You even stole my dreams!
Isn't Prince Herneval the one
desperate to get your stories, by
any means necessary?
Yes! You both are nothing but thieves!
I understand how you're feeling.
Oh, it's such a tragic tale of love,
your lover betrayed you,
because he never cared for you at all,
he only… used you.
Ah…
Mm…
Ah!
Lock her up.
-Uh-huh. Your wish is my command, my Lord.
-Ah!
Ah! Ah!
Ah!
-And you will keep writing stories for me.
-Ah!
Ah!
No!
-Ah!
-I shall find a way for you to do so.
You three…
summon the Court of Terror.
Of course, my liege.
As you wish.
Right away.
A brand new Topus Terrentus is being
born!
It's time
to come out of the dark!
She's gone.
-No…
-I don't want to hear about the terrors
or you.
-Tomorrow I leave this place for good.
-Ah…
I hope you're enjoying your new home.
Ah! Ah…
It'll be much easier if you don't try to
escape, child.
It's impossible!
You'll just tire yourself out.
Let me leave!
Why are you complaining,
Francisca? I mean, no!
Frankelda.
Wasn't this exactly what you wanted?
If not,
why did you write us,
sweetie?
Ahh!
And that's how Procustes uncovered the
betrayal Prince Herneval had been
planning.
He wanted his human to take credit
for all of our illustrious Royal
Nightmare Maker's pieces of art.
-Treachery!
And Herneval
has fled to the Realm of Existence,
he plans to conquer humans
with his charisma
and use them to dismantle the Seven
Clans.
Only then will he be able to rule
both realms!
-Treachery!
Treachery! The Topus Terrentus
could come to an end
because of the envy the Prince of Terrors
has for the Royal Nightmare Maker
-Treachery!
No! Agh! I loathe these new generations
-who foolishly go about
pretending to be human!
We have to stop this madness!
Let's take what's rightfully ours!
Death to the Royal Couple!
That pathetic prince.
And all of humankind!
-Yes!
Oh! I think this is a crisis?
I'm afraid it is too late now.
-The Topus Terrentus will disappear.
-What will become of us now? I would
like to know at once.
A time has come to take a stand
and to choose our fate together with
no guidance from the royal family.
We'll need to conspire as the realm
is now in danger. Everything we
know will fade to tragedy.
Let us save the Topus Terrentus. For a
species that's make up hurt.
He has betrayed us all he's going to
destroy our kind.
Who? Who?
The Prince of the Realm of Terrors.
He is advocating for human species.
He wants to replace us all at once.
Everything we've built, achieved, and
fought for soon enough will vanish
within his hands. He has betrayed us
all and our kingdom will tear apart.
He has betrayed us all he's going to
destroy our kind.
Who? Who?
The Prince of the Realm of Terrors.
Women, men, and children beings of
existence,
aren't aware of their to place
they think they are so special in
their ordinary realm.
He has betrayed us all, in his dreams he
will lock us up.
He has betrayed us all he's going to
imprison us.
Who? Who?
The Prince of the Realm of Terrors!
We have been banished by the Royal King.
The Clans now united, no throne
and no king. He has already
betrayed us all, our traditions he will
tear down.
He has already betrayed us all and he
will try to silence us.
Who? Who?
The Prince of the Realm of Terrors.
The time has come for us to act, let's
bring down the royal couple.
The reader shall now command and
rule us all.
What say you?
Are you with me?
-Yes!
This rebellion has to stop. Caution
has to take its hold.
Treason is what you speak of. Honor shall
prevail once more.
He wants to save us all he found an
option to save our realm.
He wants to save us all so that
the kingdom can grow and thrive.
-Who? Who?
The Prince of the Realm of Terror!
Ah!
Ahh!
Oh!
Evil traitors!
He has betrayed us all he's going to
destroy our kind.
Who? Who?
The Prince of the Realm of Terrors!
-Seize the Royal Couple.
-Yes!
I've been in this place before.
Yes!
In a prison I can't escape from.
I've been in this place before.
A sewer my dreams could shine in.
He has betrayed me too. He is a liar how
could it be?
He has betrayed me too! 'Trust in me',
that's what he said!
-Who? Who?
The Prince of the Realm of Terrors!
Calm down, our kingdom will be
forged again.
All we need is to change the course.
Stories that will call to life.
-We need her to write them down. He wants
-He wants to save us all he found an
-to save us all he found an option to
-option to save the realm.
Save the realm.
-He wants to save us all so that
-the kingdom can grow and thrive.
Who? Who?
The Prince of the Realm of Terrors!
My kingdom's in crisis, my parents
are dying,
and Frankelda hates me.
For that I am to blame now
I have betrayed them all. I shall
fall from grace.
I have betrayed them all. I know
I'm the one to blame.
So who are you?
The Prince of the Realm of Terrors!
Let's save the Topus Terrentus, for our
species to make a pact.
He has betrayed us all and now
our kingdom will tear apart.
He has betrayed us all he's going to
destroy our kind.
Who? Who?
The Prince of the Realm of Terrors!
For truth
and for fiction!
Ratha Uan Mitistaria!
Long live the King and Queen!
Ah! Ah! Ahhh!
Mh…
No! Yalabus!
No! Don't look at the Siren's eye!
Bring him to me.
Tecothians!
You swore to protect the King!
You will now obey Procustes.
I shall do so,
Milady Siren.
Huh?
-Oh!
-Victory!
Oooh…
Follow me, my terrifying leaders,
the time has come for things to change
forever.
Oh… Oh!
Ah!
Mythelitas, please, I'm begging you!
-Silence.
-No!
Stop this! I implore you to stop!
Take me instead and leave her alone!
-No!
-Ah…
-You forced my hand into this.
Now play this story.
Oh…
-My masterpiece!
-Huh?
A story about our remarkably talented
Totolina,
Hm?
That grants her an exquisite origin in
the human realm.
I feel so alive!
Woohoo!
Go ahead…
I don't understand how he's choosing.
Aww…
Oh… Muah!
Blessed miracle!
We've been waiting for this for so long!
But we can't let that witch
cross before any of us!
A being as impure as you doesn't
deserve to cross before me!
Ah! May you be cursed,
Aluxastli!
-Oh, no…
-Ow!
For once, you've done something right.
Now, write about me!
About you?
I'm way more scary than you! Write
about me, your Majesty Procustes!
Uh… uh… did we have to sign up on a list?
I don't know,
but we…
could devour every last one of them.
-The very first story must be about me,
-Oh…
Procustes.
-Agh!
-Oh…
Ready when you are, Ficturo.
Now!
They're getting away!
-Come back here!
-No…
No!
-No.
-Ah!
-Ah…
-Alright, let's all calm down! I'll write
-Ah!
-nightmares for every last one of you,
and together we'll cross in perfect
unison. Those humans will finally get
what they deserve!
I guess…
-Are we excited?
-Well, well did you hear that?
Maybe…
It's just… that you will need to give me
a little bit more time, though.
It's always the same.
After years of promising a masterpiece,
you still have the nerve to ask for
-more time.
-Why does this always happen to us?
I told you this fool wouldn't follow
through.
How is this even possible?
Francisca!
Are you here?
Francisca! Come back!
-You're alive!
-She didn't return.
You'll be alright,
I won't rest until I bring you back.
Frankelda!
Get me out of here!
Herneval?
Ahh!
I thought I wanted the best for you,
but I was only thinking of myself.
I was wrong. I know it's not much, but
I'm sorry.
Doesn't matter now, I want you to be safe.
Come, Frankelda,
let's go back to your realm.
What about your kingdom? Your parents?
You shouldn't suffer for this,
I must fix one mistake at a time.
No. We must save your parents.
But, Frankelda…
No, Herneval, I want to help them.
I want to help you.
And I know I can do it,
I have an idea that will do just the
trick.
Thank you, Frankelda but
I'm really not sure
all my plans have gone wrong,
I'm scared.
Ugh…
Well, I am not!
And I have to capture Procustes.
Sometimes I hate my reality,
but I understand that fiction wouldn't
exist without it!
If the barrier between realms falls,
all things will turn literal.
Ordinary.
No more imagination,
fascination or wonder.
Where do you plan to lock him up?
There's no stronger place than my
imagination.
What? Be careful, Frankelda!
I already made the mistake of
underestimating Procustes.
All my fears live there,
there's room for another.
No! You're risking too much.
It's not going to work!
I'm sure Procustes will force you to
send me one of his nightmares so
he can keep stealing my stories.
And when that happens,
the only thing you'll have to do
is send me one that I'll have written
myself, alright?
Trust in me.
Of course I do.
Uhm… There once was a kid named-
Bob! Eh- Bob.
Who… was hypnotized by
the… the Siren
and when he got to school
he wasn't wearing-
pants.
Ha, this is pure gold, of course.
I think I'd rather you didn't write
anything about me.
I told you earlier this is not
how writing works I need-
Even a human writes better than you.
You're a disgrace.
None of you have a place here in the
Topus Terrentus!
Oh…
The King and Queen are hurt,
I have to-
Saymuth!
-Your Highness
-No!
Save your parents.
Save the Topus Terrentus.
I'm sorry.
Mythelitas!
Mythelitas, what are you doing?
Ah…
Ow!
-If either of you dares to move again…
-Ah…
the King and Queen are history.
I'm not fooling around!
Stop, Procustes!
I'll do whatever you want.
Is… your girlfriend going to cooperate?
How does it feel to have to steal stories
-from a human?
-Ugh…
Huh?
You're a pathetic joke.
-Oh…
-Sorry…
Heh…
Send her this nightmare where she'll
live until she's written
every single story I could ever need
I'm sure her imagination will be
stimulated given the recent events.
I will then consider releasing you,
depending on your good behavior, of
course.
Ow…
Ah!
This… may seem like the story of a naive
girl who would do anything to try to
escape her reality,
but it isn't…
What is this?
This…
is the story
of a human writer who faced her fears
and decided to write her own story!
Agh!
The Nightmare Maker thought he had the
-poor girl trapped in her worst nightmare,
-Ahh!
-Ow…
-But it was her who had him.
This is not the story I wrote!
He was so obsolete and useless that he
ended up turning into his own crumbling
-house.
-Oh…
And right before entering eternal rest,
he discovered that his worst nightmare
had only just come true.
He had been replaced.
His existence was meaningless.
He had gone down in history as the most
mediocre terror of all.
He… was just a sad memory
of another time of glory.
Yes! I knew it would work!
This is definitely not the story I wrote!
Ahh! Help me!
Ah!
Procustes is changing the dream.
No!
Frankelda!
Stay away from her…
Those are…
Procustes's orders.
Please stop! Can't you see she needs help?
Frankelda, come back.
I said…
stay away!
Oh!
What happened to me?
Huh?
Frankelda.
Ah! Ah…
Frankelda,
this is your story,
not his.
Mhh…
Mh… mhh…
You think you're alone here.
That the nights belong to you,
but within the nightmares
don't trust what you can't prove.
It's my ink that stares at us.
-And my eyes rewrite you.
-Ah…
You dwell in the shadows.
In those pages you're hiding. And it's
-not so dreadful, You can see the unknown
-And it's not so dreadful, You can see the
-when you read through.
-unknown when you read through.
-This invisible ink that now lives
-without a breath,
-an author who's…
A terror!
Hm! Your tongue
-can no longer hurt me!
-Uh…
But how
piercing and cruel
its words can be.
Huh?
-Frankelda!
-Oh…
Ahh!
-Now sleep!
-Ow…
You may claim victory this round…
but I shall not be trapped in here
by myself…
We need to find a way out!
I'm sorry Frankelda,
I failed again.
Herneval?
Herneval, what's wrong?
This is just a dream, no one can hurt
you here.
Not here, no…
But I was wounded in the palace,
before I came to get you.
What? No!
No! No!
-Mh.
-It is all my fault.
It's not your fault,
you saved my parents.
Herneval, you are the only one that
matters to me.
You must find a way out of here.
You're going to be alright.
Our story was the first one I started
writing.
Thanks to you I got to know this place
I had always dreamed of visiting.
Thanks to you I got to know myself.
Our story cannot die because stories…
are immortal.
You live right here.
Huh?
Mh…
Ah…
Ah.
Ahh…
What have I done?
No!
I thought it was a nightmare,
please.
Wake up, please, wake up, Herneval.
Please don't leave us.
Ah…
-Lady Coyote!
-Ah…
Hm.
I knew you would never conspire
against us.
No!
My son!
Please, Lady Coyote,
is there anything you can do for them?
There is nothing to be done.
Your Majesties,
I cannot live with this dishonor.
I ask that my punishment
be to pay with my own life.
No, Mythelitas.
You carry a great burden,
but you're not to blame.
You are like a son to us.
We don't know where Ceimuth
sent the traitors,
but we must ensure that they cannot do
any more harm.
Find them all and bring them before us.
Beware, Mythelitas,
a great war between the Seven Clans
is about to begin.
I swear,
by Prince Herneval,
not to rest
until the last traitor
falls!
Tecothians!
For the Prince of Terrors!
Thank you, Frankelda,
I know this is not exactly
what you wanted.
But all humans
will know your stories.
Please… come back.
I am…
alive!
Where are you?
Frankelda, where are you?
-Ah!
-Ahh!
Ah…
Hello.
Huh? Who exactly…
are you?
Who do you think?
Amazing!
-Are you…?
-I am…
You are… truth!
-And fiction…
-We still exist!
Ah… As long as you tell our story,
-we'll keep existing.
-Uh…
Herneval, I love you!
I love you!
I love you too, Frankelda.
And I don't really care what form I take
as long as I can spend an eternity
with you.
Wait, what?
An… eternity like this?
That is all up to you now…
Up to me? Is it up to me after
everything we've been through?
Of course you are the writer.
Well- I'm the writer of a
sad story.
Do you really feel that way?
Well, yes!
But… sadness can…
come in different forms and shades.
A hundred authors can write the
same event
and create a hundred different stories.
Is this how your story ends, Frankelda?
I refuse to let this be how our
story ends.
I don't care how bitter my situation is,
or how long my soul has endured
confinement,
because I am the master of my destiny!
I am the writer of my own life!
Then write me!
Let's live one more time!
Yes!
This…
is the story of two realms so utterly
different, that they could resemble
each other. Two realms that do not
even exist for the numb consciousnesses.
Two realms so utterly different,
that they could resemble each other.
Two realms that do not even exist
for the numb consciousnesses.
-Two realms only visible to those who
-delve into their creativity-
guided by intuition.
Both realms are real
and they are linked by my quill.
My soul is ink,
and as long as I write
I will never stop living.